<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code Quality on On Software Development</title>
    <link>http://bilski.tech/tags/code-quality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code Quality on On Software Development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bilski.tech/tags/code-quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What do I believe in</title>
      <link>http://bilski.tech/posts/what-do-i-believe-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bilski.tech/posts/what-do-i-believe-in/</guid>
      <description>Below are my guiding principles, that are the basis of what, how and why am I doing with regards to software development.
Long term development speed First and foremost I understand my main responsibility as delivering value as fast as possible in the long term. By delivering value I mean adding, changing or removing features, that &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; requested, but also things like:
 improving processes around me, both technical, like application deployment, and business, like simplifying stock management, proposing and introducing new techniques and technologies whenever I feel that they will improve things, sharing knowledge within and outside of the team (blog, mentoring, pair/crowd programming, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code quality as a winning factor</title>
      <link>http://bilski.tech/posts/code-quality-as-a-winning-factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bilski.tech/posts/code-quality-as-a-winning-factor/</guid>
      <description>Software development seems to me like the only discipline where practitioners can get away with producing crap. If you&amp;rsquo;re a doctor and you screw up surgery or treatment, in the worst case you will kill your patient, in the best you will not make his/her situation worse. If you&amp;rsquo;re a bridge builder and you&amp;rsquo;ll make a mistake during construction, in the worst case the bridge will collapse killing people, in the best case, the bridge will be usable only after adding some additional support to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>