<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on On Software Engineering</title>
    <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/various/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on On Software Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.bilski.tech/posts/various/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Familiarity - friend or foe</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/familiarity-friend-or-foe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/familiarity-friend-or-foe/</guid>
      <description>Familiarity seems like a good thing, you know the thing, how to deal with it, what to expect and where problems might be hiding. But more and more I see its dark side.
Some time ago I was working on a legacy system. It was very complex and fragile, most developers didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have anything to do with it. We knew the time would come when we would need to touch the core of this monster, so we wrote some tests and started slowly cleaning it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing is storytelling</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/testing-is-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/testing-is-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>While working with a customer, I recently saw a test, that looked like this: throw a big XML (&amp;gt;10kB) at a function, get another XML of similar size back and compare it with a pre-recorded one. The test is green if they&amp;rsquo;re equal. I guess, at the very minimum, it serves a purpose of detecting issues. The problem is that it cannot do much more.
What such a test is not providing are hints as to what the problem is when it fails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding decomposed</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/understanding-decomposed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/understanding-decomposed/</guid>
      <description>I previously wrote about simplicity and how it helps to understand software code. In that post, I already mentioned the use of concepts like set theory. I’d like to expand on this and show how to boost readability of code.
Despite what people might think, our main purpose as developers is not writing software, but solving problems. A code is just a means, not the goal. Nobody demands software just for the sake of it from a developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting understanding with simplicity</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/supporting-understanding-with-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/supporting-understanding-with-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago, my colleague Joy Clark wrote about simplicity . I&amp;rsquo;ve also approached this topic once before. I&amp;rsquo;d like to follow up on both articles and show how simplicity can boost our understanding of software. I will also propose that we look at other disciplines to see if and how simplicity affects them. Maybe we can benefit from their experience.
What&amp;rsquo;s all the fuss about? Why do we even talk about simplicity?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do I believe in</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/what-do-i-believe-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/what-do-i-believe-in/</guid>
      <description>Below are my guiding principles, that are the basis of what, how and why am I doing with regards to software development.
Long term development speed First and foremost I understand my main responsibility as delivering value as fast as possible in the long term. By delivering value I mean adding, changing or removing features, that &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; requested, but also things like:
 improving processes around me, both technical, like application deployment, and business, like simplifying stock management, proposing and introducing new techniques and technologies whenever I feel that they will improve things, sharing knowledge within and outside of the team (blog, mentoring, pair/crowd programming, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code quality as a winning factor</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/code-quality-as-a-winning-factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/code-quality-as-a-winning-factor/</guid>
      <description>Software development seems to me like the only discipline where practitioners can get away with producing crap. If you&amp;rsquo;re a doctor and you screw up surgery or treatment, in the worst case you will kill your patient, in the best you will not make his/her situation worse. If you&amp;rsquo;re a bridge builder and you&amp;rsquo;ll make a mistake during construction, in the worst case the bridge will collapse killing people, in the best case, the bridge will be usable only after adding some additional support to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing good test scenarios</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/writing-good-test-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/writing-good-test-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>On my current company&amp;rsquo;s blog I posted some time ago part one of &amp;ldquo;writing good tests&amp;rdquo; . Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to continue.
Last time I just barely scratched the topic of writing test scenarios. I briefly gave only a few hints like &amp;ldquo;avoid unnecessary information&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t include implementation details&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself in different scenarios&amp;rdquo;. This time I&amp;rsquo;d like to dig deeper and present results of discussions we had in the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices - a solution or a problem?</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/microservices-a-solution-or-a-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/microservices-a-solution-or-a-problem/</guid>
      <description>Microservices seem to be everywhere, everybody is talking about them, writing and consuming them. For a good reason, they can solve a lot of problems like scaling, high availability, independent developability, etc. But are they really THE solution to our problems? Do we always remember their costs?
Integration One of the good things about microservices is, that they&amp;rsquo;re simple. Each one should be easy to understand even by a new person joining a team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on MyFaces and ContentType</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/more-on-myfaces-and-contenttype/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/more-on-myfaces-and-contenttype/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve dug some more, debugged some more and know a little more. The whole problem with Apache MyFaces and ContentType comes from the awful idea that there is more than one moment, when, for a single request, resulting ContentType is evaluated.
MyFaces looks at Accept HTTP header, which, in my case, states text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,*/*;q=0.8. MyFaces goes through that list and picks first entry which it understands, in my case that&amp;rsquo;s text/html. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter, that next entry application/xhtml+xml is what I would really want, &amp;ldquo;text/html&amp;rdquo; was first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including JavaScript in HTML content</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/including-javascript-in-html-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/including-javascript-in-html-content/</guid>
      <description>For the last couple of days, I was struggling with Java ServerFaces. The exact problem was, that commandButtons were working as expected, but commandLinks were not. We are using Apache MyFaces with Tomahawk and Sandbox components. We were going to use commandLinks for navigation and other uses like selecting nodes in Tomahawks&amp;rsquo; tree2 component, but we were forced to render commandButtons instead, which looked quite awkward in some places.
Symptoms we got, were that three browsers: Firefox, Opera and Konqueror, were complaining about &amp;ldquo;oamSubmitForm is not defined&amp;rdquo; after clicking a commandLink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autowiring EJB 3.0 in Tomcat from remote JBoss</title>
      <link>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/autowiring-ejb-3.0-in-tomcat-from-remote-jboss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bilski.tech/posts/autowiring-ejb-3.0-in-tomcat-from-remote-jboss/</guid>
      <description>To be honest I&amp;rsquo;ve never fully understood EJB 2.x or written an application using that specification. Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve written some EJBs, but it was just following an example of different EJB in the same project. Even though we used Spring at that time nothing seemed simple and straightforward. Every time I wanted to use an EJB I had to modify several XML files to be able to inject EJB into some bean.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>